Guide to the Pleasant Valley Wine Company records,1859-1965
Pleasant Valley Wine Company records, 1860-1953
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Pleasant Valley Wine Company records, 1859-1965.
6599
Pleasant Valley Wine Company.
ca. 70 cubic ft.
Correspondence, Financial Records, Legal Documents, Memorabilia, Newspapers, Printed Materials, Reports.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
This collection documents administrative and financial affairs of the Pleasant Valley Wine Company through its founding in 1860 through the 1950s. Included are grape growing and vineyard records, business ledgers, retail sales reports and statistics, correspondence from manufacturers, wholesalers and clients, advertising material, tax returns and other government correspondence. Correspondence with the company's traveling salesmen document the economic and social conditions of the time, especially in the period leading up to and during Prohibition. Government legislation, taxation, and regulation of alcohol is documented through legal forms, permits, and correspondence. Also included are various types of ephemera such as bottle labels, menus, advertising, and other promotional material, including a videotape, The Story of Wine, and a Betacam SP videotape, Pleasant Valley Wines. Also contains extensive business and personal correspondence of Champlin, Bauder, and Masson.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
The Hammondsport and Pleasant Valley Wine Company was established on March 15, 1860 by Charles Davenport Champlin and twelve area businessmen. The company was designated as Bonded Winery No.1 in its state and federal districts. In 1865 Joseph Masson became the wine-maker and around this time the production of sparkling wine was initiated. This wine, which was marketed under the brand name Great Western, became the first American sparkling wine to win an award in Europe. The awards included first prizes in Vienna, 1873; Paris 1889; Brussels, 1897; Paris, 1900; and Brussels in 1910. In the late 19th and early 20th centuries the company had many prestigious personal and business accounts. Between 1872 and 1875, Charles Champlin and his associates built the nine-mile Bath to Hammondsport Railroad in order to compete with canal transportation.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
This collection documents administrative and financial affairs of the Pleasant Valley Wine Company through its founding in 1860 through the 1950s. Included are grape growing and vineyard records, business ledgers, retail sales reports and statistics, correspondence from manufacturers, wholesalers and clients, advertising material, tax returns and other government correspondence. Correspondence with the company's traveling salesmen document the economic and social conditions of the time, especially in the period leading up to and during Prohibition. Government legislation, taxation, and regulation of alcohol is documented through legal forms, permits, and correspondence. Also included are various types of ephemera such as bottle labels, menus, advertising, and other promotional material, including a videotape, The Story of Wine, and a Betacam SP videotape, Pleasant Valley Wines. Also contains extensive business and personal correspondence of Champlin, Bauder, and Masson.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Pleasant Valley Wine Company.; Pleasant Valley Wine Company.
Subjects:
Grape industry--New York (State).; Wineries--New York (State)--Finger Lakes Region.; Wine and wine making--New York (State)--Finger Lakes Region.; Wine industry--Government policy--United States.; Wine--Marketing.; Wine industry--United States--Quality control.; Vineyards--New York (State)--Finger Lakes Region.; Viticulture--United States.; Grapes--Varieties.; Prohibition--Economic aspects--United States.; Prohibition--New York (State)--History--20th century.; Taxation--New York (State).; Internal revenue--New York (State).; Wine and wine making--Law and legislation.; Liquor laws--United States--History--20th century.; Wine industry--New York (State)--Finger Lakes Region.; Viticulture--New York (State).
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
A 1955 Cornell industrial engineering student report on the PVWC can be found in collection 16-2-2244, Andrew Schultz Schultz, Jr. Papers. See accession folder for report table of contents. Accession folder also contains 1952 letter to University Archivist Edith M. Fox from Pleasant Valley president, R. H. Howell.
CONTAINER LIST
- Assorted Papers and Correspondence, 1859-1971
  - Papers, Includes 1865 winery license., 1859 - August 1867 (Box 1)
  - Papers, includes 1967 Ithaca advertisement for Wheel Rake, September 1867 - October 1869 (Box 2)
  - Papers, November 1869 - June 1871 (Box 3)
  - Papers, July 1871 - June 1872 (Box 4)
  - Papers, includes flyer for Vienna Exposition listing Professor George Caldwell, constitution of the Cosmopolite Club, July 1872 - June 1873 (Box 5)
  - Papers, July 1873 - May 1874 (Box 6)
  - Papers, June 1874 - May 1875 (Box 7)
  - Papers, June 1875 - December 1876 (Box 8)
  - Papers, 1877 - 1878 (Box 9)
  - Papers, includes folder of letters from John Cass, salesman., 1879 - 1881 (Box 10)
  - Papers, 1882 - 1884 (Box 11)
  - Papers, Text of speech on history of Keuka Lake wine-making, 1885 - April 1887 (Box 12)
  - Papers, May 1887 - June 1889 (Box 13)
  - Papers, July 1889 - January 1891 (Box 14)
  - Papers, 1891 - July 1892 (Box 15)
  - Papers, August 1892 - 1893 (Box 16)
  - Papers, includes Bauder Family/Personal correspondence (1894-1896) Letter mentioning Cornell trustee Samuel Halliday & Groton School Board U.S. Express Co. correspondence (1892-1904), 1894 - April 1895 (Box 17)
  - Papers, includes letter from Bauder's son about attending Temperance lecture, May 1895 - November 1896 (Box 18)
  - Papers, December 1896 - August 1898 (Box 19)
  - Papers, September 1898 - September 1899 (Box 20)
  - Papers, November 1899 - August 1900 (Box 21)
  - Papers, September 1900 - December 1901 (Box 22)
  - Papers, includes Bauder personal correspondence and advertising (1901), 1901 - 1902 (Box 23)
  - Papers, 1903 - February 1904 (Box 24)
  - Papers, includes letter from Sherman Peer of the Cornellian yearbook about advertising, March 1904 - August 1905 (Box 25)
  - Papers, includes Bauder Family/Personal correspondence (1905-1906) Correspondence with Knapp winery. Sept 28, 1905 letter from George Washington University about adding the Paris Exposition gold medal to the wine label, also mentions Minister to Belgium enjoying wine (Pers. Cor. G folder) March 26, 1906 on registering the words "Great Western"., September 1905 - 1906 (Box 26)
  - Papers, includes some correspondence from 1907-1910, 1907 - August 1908 (Box 27)
  - Papers, includes receipts, misc (1907-1910), September 1908 - December 1909 (Box 28)
  - Papers, includes advertising correspondence (1909), 1909 - April 1911 (Box 29)
  - Papers, May 1911 - November 1912 (Box 30)
  - Papers, very little material from 1913 and 1914, December 1913 - 1915 (Box 31)
  - Papers, includes wine tax, anti-prohibition legislation papers, 1915 - 1916 (Box 32)
  - Papers, includes sprinkler system correspondence (1912-1917), 1916 - 1917 (Box 33)
  - Papers, 1917 - 1918 (Box 34)
  - Papers, 1919 (Box 35)
  - Papers, includes notes about Congressional election between Cornellians Frank Irvine and Lewis Henry and correspondence with Cornell Chemistry Department, 1919 - 1920s (Box 36)
  - Papers, includes certificate of compliance with National Prohibition Director and letter from customer requesting medicinal champagne. One folder marked 1929 in back also contains items from 1900s, 1920s (Box 37)
  - Papers, 1920s (Box 38)
  - Papers, prohibition permits, IRS forms, tax information., 1916-1931 (Box 39)
  - Papers, revenue tax, Cornell Ag school letter., 1916-1929 (Box 40)
  - Papers, labels, wine analysis, Wine Embassy paper on increasing wine sales., 1930-1938 (Box 41)
  - Papers, 1926-1937 (Box 42)
  - Papers, 1930-1938 (Box 43)
  - Papers, 1934-1938 (Box 44)
  - Papers, 1937 (Box 45)
  - Papers, 1937-1938 (Box 46)
  - Papers, includes letter from James Wadsworth, noted anti-Prohibition Congressman, 1939-1940 (Box 47)
  - Papers, 1940 - 1941 (Box 48)
  - Papers, 1941-1942 (Box 49)
  - Papers, 1942 - 1943 (Box 50)
  - Papers, 1943 - 1945 (Box 51)
  - Papers, 1945-1947 (Box 52)
  - Papers, includes letter to Professor Emile Chamot also letters to various New York State Agriculture Experiment Station employees, Hedrick, Wellington, Boyce, etc., also a United States map from 1951 showing the percentages of individuals who eat meals out in principal cities, importace of hotels and resteraunts, hotel and resteraunt business statistics, number of important resteraunts, number of hotels open year round with 50 or more rooms, etc. all by state, from Ahrens Publising Company.., 1947-1952 (Box 53)
  - Papers, 1952 - 1953 (Box 54)
  - Papers, includes IRS forms from the 1920s. 152 page 1955 report done by Cornell University students for Professor Byron Saunders consulting on the Pleasant Valley Wine Company on how to increase efficiency, this includes engineering aspects and drawings. The Grape Leaf publication of the Pleasant Valley Wine co., Volume 3 Issue 1, and Volume 4 Issue 3, 1971, includes picture of New York Mets celebrating pennant with Great Western champagne. Includes undated material, 1915-1920s, 1953, 1955, 1963 - 1965, 1971 (Box 55)
  - Ephemera, Misc, Menus, Wine Lists, Advertising, Photos, Stock certificates. Sacramental wine ads, Cornellinan correspondence, prohibition menu. (Box 56)
  - Ephemera, Misc, Advertising, labels, includes a Great western grape juice label. Publicity photos, biography of C.D. Champlin, poster supporting beer in the army. Very early photo of company building showing Bauder on the porch. 1890 Grapes bought booklet and employee expense brochures. Medicinal wine and prohibition ads. Grape Ketchup ad. (Box 57)
  - Ephemera, Misc, Advertising Anti-Prohibition ad, Kortlander Bros Grand Rapid Michigan wine label, 1867 Urbana ad with note about competition, newspaper on Hammondsport wine-making history, Masson biography, taxes, misc. correspondence. Folder of misc visual items including some labels, receipts, envelopes, irs report, brochure for Friars Old Monastery Champagne Rheims N.Y., NY assembly bills on liquor laws and prohibition, American Champagne Makers Association brochure, Ukiah Grape Products Company booklet, Johannaber Wine Vaults card. Also a folder of voting proxies / stockholder information from early 1900s through 1933. This folder includes the letter from Victor Masson announcing his resignation from the board, this folder also contains drafts of photo postcards of the winery. (Box 58)
  - "Pleasent Valley Wines" videocassette, V-10706 (Box 58)
  - Copy of bill of complaint from equity suit filed by California Wine association of New York in the Supreme Court of the District of Columbia, April 21, 1926 against Internal Revenue for not allowing them to sell of wine to Jewish Rabbis for sacramental purposes. Inventories, Misc, Champlin Deed/Mortgage, Advertising (some nice color ones ca. 1930), Clippings, Scrapbook pages, blank forms. 1919 NY Liquor tax license. Also includes a handwritten history of the winery written ca. 1873, that includes lists of all awards won and text from press coverage on the winery. Also History of the Officers and Directors and Dividends, 1860-1933, compiled by F. M. Aulls September 1970, includes James Champlin Bauder obituary. Also 1862 letter from directors to firm discussing the requirements for building new cellar. Several letters from 1861-1862 in German to John F. Weber, PV superintendent, showing distillery plans. (Box 59)
  - IRS ledger book, account book, letterbooks (Box 60)
  - Letterbooks includes letters from Jules Masson, 1898-1902 (Box 61)
  - Letterbooks includes chemistry notebook (Box 62)
  - Letterbooks (Box 63)
  - Letterbooks (Box 64)
  - Letterbooks (Box 65)
  - Letterbooks includes account books (Box 66)
  - Accounts payable, sales records (Box 67)
  - Account books, tierage records (Box 68)
  - Sales records (Box 69)
  - Wine labels (unsorted) (Box 70)
  - Wines and Vines Vol. 39 No. 7, 1958-07 (Box 88, Folder 1)
  - Pleasant Valley Wine Bottle Labels, Undated (Box 88, Folder 2)
  - Pleasant Valley Wine Bottle Labels, Undated (Box 88, Folder 3)
  - Assorted Bottle Labels, Undated (Box 88, Folder 4)
  - Presidential Wine Glasses, Undated (Box 88, Folder 5)
  - PV Correspondence 1 of 3, 1866-1904 (Box 88, Folder 6)
  - PV Correspondence 2 of 3, 1865-1921 (Box 88, Folder 7)
  - PV Correspondence 2 of 3, 1906-1919 (Box 88, Folder 8)
  - Envelopes, Postcards, and Pamphlets, 1900-1950 (Box 88, Folder 9)
  - Pleasant Valley Correspondence, Date Unknown (Box 88, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1885-11 (Box 88, Folder 11)
  - A-G Correspondence 1 of 2, 1897 (Box 88, Folder 12)
  - H-Z Correspondence 2 of 2, 1897 (Box 88, Folder 13)
  - A-J Correspondence 1 of 2, 1909-03 (Box 88, Folder 14)
  - K-Z Correspondence 2 of 2, 1909-03 (Box 88, Folder 15)
  - A-J Advertising Correspondence 1 of 2, 1912 (Box 88, Folder 16)
  - L-Z Advertising Correspondence 2 of 2, 1912 (Box 88, Folder 17)
  - A-L Advertisement Invoices 1 of 2, 1915 (Box 88, Folder 18)
  - M-Z Advertisement Invoices 2 of 2, 1915 (Box 88, Folder 19)
  - Business Correspondence Pleasant Valley, 1870-08 (Box 89, Folder 1)
  - Business Correspondence Pleasant Valley A-J, 1889-01-1889-02 (Box 89, Folder 2)
  - Business Correspondence Pleasant Valley K-Z, 1889-01-1889-02 (Box 89, Folder 3)
  - Business Correspondence Pleasant Valley A-J, 1893-12 (Box 89, Folder 4)
  - Business Correspondence Pleasant Valley K-Z, 1893-12 (Box 89, Folder 5)
  - Business Correspondence Pleasant Valley A-G, 1896-08 (Box 89, Folder 6)
  - Business Correspondence Pleasant Valley H-Z, 1896-08 (Box 89, Folder 7)
  - Business Correspondence Bauder A-G, 1899-05 (Box 89, Folder 8)
  - Business Correspondence Bauder H-W, 1899-05 (Box 89, Folder 9)
  - Business Correspondence Pleasant Valley A-G, 1908-01-1908-02 (Box 89, Folder 10)
  - Business Correspondence Pleasant Valley H-Z, 1908-01-1908-02 (Box 89, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1884-1890 (Box 89, Folder 12)
  - Bauder Family Correspondence, 1888-1890 (Box 89, Folder 13)
  - Other Bauder Correspondence, 1890 (Box 89, Folder 14)
  - St. John Military School Evaluations, 1889-1890 (Box 89, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1901 (Box 89, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1916 (Box 89, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1919 (Box 89, Folder 18)
  - Great Western Sales Inc. Correspondence, 1931 (Box 89, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1931 (Box 89, Folder 20)
  - F. M. Champlin Correspondence, 1931-1932 (Box 89, Folder 21)
  - P.P. Stargis Correspondence, 1931-1932 (Box 89, Folder 22)
  - Frank Nickerson Correspondence, 1931-1932 (Box 89, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, 1932 (Box 89, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, 1933 (Box 89, Folder 25)
  - Pleasant Valley Great Western Advertising and Pricelists, 1940-1945 (Box 89, Folder 26)
  - Invoices and Correspondence, 1885-1900 (Box 90)
- Ledgers, 1875-1965
  - Letters Books, 1901-1931
    - Gold Seal Letters Book, 1901-09-01-1901-12-09 (Box 72)
    - Gold Seal Letters Book, 1911-12-19-1912-02-19 (Box 72)
    - Gold Seal Letters Book, 1914-04-28-1914-06-30 (Box 72)
    - Gold Seal Letters Book, 1914-09-14-1914-10-31 (Box 72)
    - Gold Seal Letters Book, 1917-04-18-1917-06-14 (Box 72)
    - Gold Seal Letters Book, 1918-02-01-1918-04-16 (Box 72)
    - Gold Seal Letters Book, 1918-07-09-1918-10-23 (Box 72)
    - Gold Seal Letters Book, 1918-12-27-1919-02-25 (Box 74)
    - Gold Seal Letters Book, 1919-02-25-1919-05-11 (Box 74)
    - Gold Seal Letters Book, 1930-12-08-1931-10-08 (Box 74)
  - Check Ledgers, 1896-1941
    - Pleasant Valley Checks 22000 to 28999, 1896-04-1898-11 (Volume 30)
    - Bank of Hammondsport Check Stub Book, 1935-1936 (Box 74)
    - Pleasant Valley Check Stub Book, 1930-1934 (Box 74)
    - Check Stub Book, 1940-1941 (Box 74)
  - Order Ledgers, 1890-1922
    - Pleasant Valley Orders No. 11, 1890-1892 (Box 76)
    - Pleasant Valley Orders No. 12, 1892-07-1894-08 (Box 76)
    - Pleasant Valley Orders No. 13, 1894-08-1896-08 (Box 79)
    - Pleasant Valley Orders No. 14, 1896-10-1898-07 (Box 73)
    - Pleasant Valley Orders No. 16, 1900-1901 (Box 75)
    - Pleasant Valley Orders No. 17, 1901-11-1903-04 (Box 79)
    - Pleasant Valley Orders No. 18, 1903-04-1904-11 (Box 80)
    - Pleasant Valley Orders No. 19, 1904-11-1906-09 (Box 80)
    - Pleasant Valley Orders No. 20, 1906-09-1908-06 (Box 81)
    - Pleasant Valley Orders No. 21, 1908-06-1910-01 (Box 81)
    - Pleasant Valley Orders Book, 1910-1911 (Box 73)
    - Pleasant Valley Orders No. 23, 1911-05-1912-10 (Box 85)
    - Pleasant Valley Orders No. 24, 1912-10-1913-12 (Box 77)
    - Pleasant Valley Orders No. 25, 1913-1915 (Box 77)
    - Pleasant Valley Orders No. 26, 1915-11-1917-04 (Box 82)
    - Pleasant Valley Orders No. 27, 1917-04-1922-09 (Box 82)
  - Shipping Ledgers, 1876-1933
    - Pleasant Valley Shipping, 1876-06-1879-09 (Box 83)
    - Pleasant Valley Shipping, 1879-12-1882-03 (Box 78)
    - Pleasant Valley Shipping, 1882-03-1884-07 (Box 83)
    - Pleasant Valley Shipping, 1884-07-1887-03 (Box 84)
    - Pleasant Valley Shipping, 1889-05-1891-04 (Box 84)
    - Pleasant Valley Shipping, 1895-08-1897-09 (Box 85)
    - Pleasant Valley Shipping, 1914-09-1916-07 (Box 78)
    - Pleasant Valley Shipping, 1918-1933 (Box 71)
  - Cash Books, 1880-1933
    - Pleasant Valley Cash Book No. 2, 1880-1884 (Volume 1)
    - Pleasant Valley Cash Book No. 3, 1884-1889 (Volume 2)
    - Pleasant Valley Cash Book No. 4, 1889-1894 (Volume 3)
    - Pleasant Valley Cash Book No. 5, 1894-1899 (Volume 4)
    - Pleasant Valley Cash Book No. 6, 1899-1903 (Volume 5)
    - Pleasant Valley Cash Book No. 8, 1908-1912 (Volume 6)
    - Pleasant Valley Cash Book No. 9, 1912-1916 (Volume 7)
    - Pleasant Valley Cash Book No. 10, 1916-1924 (Volume 8)
    - Pleasant Valley Cash Book No. 11, 1931-1933 (Volume 9)
  - Sales Ledgers, 1875-1936
    - Pleasant Valley Sales Book No. 1, 1875-1879 (Volume 10)
    - Pleasant Valley Sales Book No. 2, 1879-1882 (Volume 11)
    - Pleasant Valley Sales Book No. 3, 1882-08-1885-09 (Volume 12)
    - Pleasant Valley Sales Book No. 4, 1885-1888 (Volume 13)
    - Pleasant Valley Sales Book No. 7, 1894-1898 (Volume 14)
    - Pleasant Valley Sales Book No. 8, 1898-1900 (Volume 15)
    - Pleasant Valley Sales Book No. 9, 1901-1902 (Volume 16)
    - Great Western Sales Book No. 10, 1902-11-1905-02 (Volume 17)
    - Pleasant Valley Sales Book, 1905-1907 (Volume 18)
    - Pleasant Valley Sales Book, 1907-1909 (Volume 19)
    - Pleasant Valley Sales Book No. 13, 1910-01-1912-02 (Volume 20)
    - Pleasant Valley Sales Book No. 14, 1912-02-1914-01 (Volume 21)
    - Great Western Sales Book No. 15, 1914-06-1916-10 (Volume 22)
    - Pleasant Valley Sales Book No. 16, 1916-10-1919-03 (Volume 23)
    - Pleasant Valley Sales Book No.17, 1919-1930 (Volume 24)
    - Montage Vineyards Co. Sales Book, 1934-1936 (Volume 62)
  - Teazer Ledgers, 1882-1915
    - Pleasant Valley Teazer No. 2, 1882-11-1890-12 (Volume 25)
    - Pleasant Valley Teaser No. 3, 1889-09-1896-12 (Volume 26)
    - Pleasant Valley Teazer No. 4, 1887-01-1893-09 (Volume 27)
    - Pleasant Valley Teazer No. 5, 1903-10-1910-04 (Volume 28)
    - Pleasant Valley Teazer No. 6, 1910-05-1915-09 (Volume 29)
  - Day Books, 1885-1905
    - Pleasant Valley Day Book, 1885-1893 (Volume 31)
    - Pleasant Valley Day Book No. I, 1893-1905 (Volume 32)
  - Fermentation Ledgers, 1955-1964
    - Pleasant Valley Wine Fermentation Record, 1955-01-1957-05 (Volume 41)
    - Pleasant Valley & Great Western Wine Fermentation Record, 1957-09-1959-08 (Volume 42)
    - Great Western Fermentation Records 2054, 1959-09-1961-05 (Volume 43)
    - Great Western Wine Fermentation Record, 1961-09-1962-10 (Volume 44)
    - Taylor Wine Co. Wine Fermentation Record, 1962-07-1963-06 (Volume 45)
    - Taylor Wine Co. Wine Fermentation Record, 1963-07-1964-06 (Volume 46)
  - Effervescent Ledgers, 1955-1962
    - Pleasant Valley Record of Effervescent Wine, 1955-01-1957-04 (Volume 47)
    - Pleasant Valley Record of Effervescent Wine, 1957-05-1959-04 (Volume 48)
    - Great Western Record of Effervescent Wine, 1959-05-1960-07 (Volume 49)
    - Great Western Champagne Form 2057, 1960-07-1961-12 (Volume 50)
    - Taylor Wine Co. Record of Effervescent Wine, 1962-01-1962-07 (Volume 51)
  - Still Wine Ledgers, 1955-1965
    - Pleasant Valley Record of Still Wines, 1955-02-1956-11 (Volume 52)
    - Pleasant Valley & Great Western Record of Still Wine, 1956-12-1958-10 (Volume 53)
    - Great Western Still Wine Records 2056, 1958-11-1960-04 (Volume 54)
    - Great Western Record of Still Wine, 1960-05-1961-08 (Volume 55)
    - Great Western Record of Still Wine, 1961-09-1962-07 (Volume 56)
    - Pleasant Valley Record of Still Wine, 1962-1965-06 (Volume 57)
  - Other Wine Reocrds, 1955-1962
    - Pleasant Valley & Great Western Special Natural Wine Production Record 2058, 1955-1962 (Volume 58)
    - Pleasant Valley, Great Western, & Taylor Wine Co. Wine Reserve Inventory Record 2055, 1955-1962 (Volume 59)
    - Old 702 Forms, 1955-01-1959-12 (Volume 60)
    - Great Western Record of Bottled Wine, 1960-07-1961-06 (Volume 61)
  - Other Assorted Ledgers, 1865-1963
    - E Ledger, Undated (Volume 35)
      Blank
    - Pleasant Valley Ledger (Box 86)
    - Pleasant Valley Day Book A, 1865-1868 (Box 87)
    - Day Book, 1865-04-1876-06 (Box 87)
    - Champlin & Rose Hammondsport Journal, 1866-1867 (Box 71)
    - Ledger, 1871-1875 (Box 86)
    - Pleasant Valley Ledger, 1887 (Box 74)
    - Pleasant Valley Ledger No. K, 1889-1891 (Volume 36)
    - Invoices, 1891-1904 (Volume 34)
    - Pleasant Valley Ledger No. L, 1892-01-1894-05 (Volume 37)
    - C.N.Y.G.G.U. Ledger, 1893 (Volume 33)
    - Pleasant Valley Ledger No. M, 1896-1900 (Volume 38)
    - Pleasant Valley Ledger No. N, 1900-1905 (Volume 39)
    - Pleasant Valley Ledger No. O, 1906-1914 (Volume 40)
    - Pleasant Valley Ledger, 1930-10-1932-04 (Box 74)
    - Pleasant Valley Winemakers Production Record, 1950-03-1950-09 (Box 75)
    - Taylor Wine Co. Inventory of Wine, 1960-01-1963-12 (Box 75)